lotuscars.com 2018-09-09

# Privacy Policy | Lotus Cars

Group Lotus plc ("Lotus") takes your privacy seriously and is committed to protecting it.

This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please take the time to review this policy so that you understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.  
 **  
INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**  
We may collect the following data about you:

  * Information provided by you by filling in forms on our site. 
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfillment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to our site and the resources that you access.

**IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES**  
We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is statistical data analysed for browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

For the same purposes, Lotus may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To recognise you when you return to our site.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, by doing so, you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**  
The data collected from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. Lotus will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password enabling you to access certain parts of our site, it is your responsibility to keep this password confidential. Please do not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. While we will do our best to protect your personal data, Lotus cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site.  Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**  
We use the information collected:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may contact you by email, post or telephone. 

Additionally, we may use your personal data [in an anonymous form] to analyse our customer profiles and for statistical purposes. We may share this anonymised statistical information with third parties as part of market research purposes. We may also share your personal data with companies within the Lotus group of companies and selected third party companies.  
Lotus will not rent out or sell our customer lists to any other organisation.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**  
We may disclose your personal information to other members of our group of companies. 

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Lotus or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by Lotus about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Lotus, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**  
YOUR RIGHTS**  
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [webmaster@lotuscars.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@lotuscars.com) or at:

Webmaster, Group Lotus plc, Potash Lane, Hethel, Norwich, Norfolk NR14 8EZ UK.

You have the right to object to the processing, restrict or stop processing or request deletion of the personal data we hold on you. If you do ask us to delete or stop processing it, we may not be required to do so if legislation does not allow us to, i.e. for safety issues.

Our website may contain links to other websites that may be of interest to you but which are outside of our group.  Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to our website.  Websites which are linked from our website may not have privacy policies or they may use your personal information in ways which are different to those set out in this policy. Lotus is not responsible for the content, privacy or security of other websites.

**ACCESS TO INFORMATION**  
You have the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any excessive or unfounded access request may be subject to a reasonable fee to meet our administration costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.  
 **  
CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**  
This privacy policy may be amended from time to time and amendments published on our websites.

**CONTACT**  
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to us at [webmaster@lotuscars.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@lotuscars.com) or at:

Webmaster, Group Lotus plc, Potash Lane, Hethel, Norwich, Norfolk NR14 8EZ UK.

If you are not happy, or have a complaint about the way we use your personal information, we hope that you will contact us at the above address. If you are not satisfied, you may also make a complaint to the Information Commissioners office which is the supervisory authority who regulates personal data in the UK.
